François-Xavier Decarpentrie - Product Designer UX/UI

# 10+ years of experience conducting research and testing, facilitating workshops, prototyping and designing digital products and services.

# French citizen available for freelance & long-term opportunities

+33(0)6 36 09 97 36 fdecarpentrie@gmail.com f-xd.me

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### Freelance

Senior Product Designer. 01/2024 - Present - Paris

Client: L'Oréal (Research & Innovation)

- Principal UX/UI Designer responsible for all the digital tools and services used by chemists
- Designed a GenAl chatbot based on GPT4 to help chemists identify the best perfoming formulas

Senior Product Designer. 11/2023 - 12/2023 - Paris

Client: Biogen (Biogen Digital Health)

• Created and prototyped a mobile app to help Japanese patients suffering from Spinal muscular atrophy (SMA) track the evolution of their symptoms

Innovation Designer. 5/2022 - 10/2023 - Paris

Client: Valeo (France #1 global automotive supplier)

- Prototyped and tested AR/VR/XR experiences (entertainment, gaming, ADAS)
- Conducted user research and workshops around the use of video in vehicle

Product Designer. 2014 - 2022 - Various locations

Clients: Accor, Sanofi, OUI.sncf, Samurai Trip, 4th Valley, DigitasLbi, Nissan

• Converted conceptual visions into a coherent and convincing UX strategy and translated complex matters into simple solutions

#### R/GA

Senior Experience Designer (contract). 7/2019 - 12/2019 - Melbourne

Client: Toyota Australia

- Prepared and facilitated design thinking workshops with the design team (10 people) to reach consensus on the creation of the design system
- Built interfaces and prototypes to support discussions in a cross-functional team

#### Isobar

Senior Experience Designer. 8/2018 - 7/2019 - Melbourne

Client: Holden (Australian automobile manufacturer)

- Conducted interviews to capture user needs and insights and particularly to understand online habits and mindsets of customers in market for a new car
- Combined user and data insights and business goals into wireframes and prototypes

#### Microcred (Baobab Group)

UX Manager. 6/2016 - 7/2017 - Paris

- Lead and trained a team of 3 UX/UI designers
- Conducted customer interviews in Senegal and Madagascar to capture user needs

# Razorfish (Publicis.Sapient)

Lead UX Designer. 8/2014 - 12/2015 - Shanghai

Clients: Nike, Heineken, Unilever food solutions, GrandVision

• Created functional designs for web & mobile apps and digital campaign

#### **SKILLS**

Wireframing

Rapid prototyping

Research (qualitative & quantitative)

Usability testing

Information architecture

Workshop facilitation

Agile SCRUM

HTML, CSS, JS

### **TOOLS**

Blender

Figma, Sketch Photoshop, Illustrator After Effects Unity

# **LANGUAGES**

French Native

English Fluent TOIEC 990

Japanese Business JLPT N2

Chinese Conversational

#### **EDUCATION**

2011 Advanced Master
Digital Project Conception
TELECOM Paristech, Paris

2009 Master's degree

Asian Afairs

IEP, Lyon

2008 Studying abroad

Dokkyo Daigaku

Soka-shi, Saitama-ken, Japan

